ELAINE P. JACINTO

UX/UI Designer

(909) 784-0870 | elainejac@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elainejacinto

Portfolio: https://elainejac.github.io/portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Certified UX/UI designer at the University of California-Irvine with skills in HTML, CSS, JQuery, Visual Prototyping & Wireframing, User Research, and Interface Development. Passionate in developing web and app designs with users in mind. Background in environmental management in healthcare and manufacturing settings along with innovative creations and functional designs make me a versatile addition to any team and project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programs: XD, InVision Languages: HTML, CSS, Libraries: Bootstrap, jQuery

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint
Strong work ethic and analytical skills
Efficient and reliable

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

Bachelor of Science, Applied Ecology

CERTIFICATIONS

UX/UI

Healthcare Environmental Management

PROJECTS

Craigslist Redesign & App Development | https://adobe.ly/2W9K9DJ

- Updated user interface of existing website to provide filter options for categories and incorporate a rating system that enables users to report potential scammers. Developed app with the new features
- Conducted user research, designed prototype and wireframing of the app, user testing, and coded a new design for the desktop webpage.
- Tools used: XD, Webflow, HTML/CSS

Bolsa Chica Conservancy Website Redesign | https://adobe.ly/2TYIIMb

- Created a responsive web design for a non-profit organization that calls attention to their purpose and offers transparency on their use of donations for users' reassurance.
- Conducted surveys/interviews with participants, performed heuristic analysis and competitor analysis, interface development, prototyping and wireframing.
- Tools used: XD, InVision, FlowMapp, Miro, Google Surveys, UXPressia

Department of the Interior Website Redesign | https://adobe.ly/2WcHfho, https://adobe.ly/3aRiKL8

• Redesigned the government website and created responsive web designs for mobile, tablet, and desktop.

ELAINE P. JACINTO

UX/UI Designer

(909) 784-0870 | <u>elainejac@gmail.com</u> Linkedin: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/elainejacinto</u>

Portfolio: https://elainejac.github.io/portfolio/

Conducted usability tests, heuristic analysis and accessibility testing of existing website, ideate
features, reorganized information architecture based on user flow, developed a new interface
design including prototyping and wireframing.

• Tools used: XD, InVision

Snooze It App | https://adobe.ly/3cKCu4C

- Create an app that serves as an alarm that works hand-in-hand with a preferred navigation system in an effort to help users get their optimal amount of sleep while eliminating the worry of hitting traffic and being late to their destination.
- Conducted user research, competitor analysis, ideation, designed prototypes and wireframing, and tested for usability.
- Tools used: XD, InVision, Miro

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Student

University of California, Irvine, CA

Sep 2019 – Mar 2020

- Create prototypes for designing web and app design interfaces.
- Maintain understanding of current web technology practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional workshop groups.
- Design, build, or maintain web sites, using scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media.
- Analyze user needs to determine technical requirements.
- Develop web site maps, application models, style guides, or page templates that meet project goals, user needs, or industry standards.

Manager, Environmental Health & Safety Department and Solutions Department

Kaiser Permanente, Chino Hills, CA

May 2016 – Present

- Inspect and evaluate workplace environments, equipment, and practices, in order to manage hazards and ensure compliance with safety standards and government regulations.
- Recommend measures to help protect workers from potentially hazardous processes or materials.
- Collaborate with staff and management to institute control and remedial measures.
- Investigate incidents to identify causes and determine solutions to prevent recurrence.
- Conduct safety training per regulatory requirements, and demonstrate safe work practices.
- Maintain and update safety policies & procedures as well as emergency response plans.
- Maintain inventories of hazardous materials and wastes, using tracking systems to ensure that materials are managed properly.

Safety Coordinator

Kaiser Permanente, Irvine, CA

Jul 2007 – May 2016